AWOSIKA OLADAPO

PRODUCT DESIGNER

oladapoawosika.o@gmail.com • LinkedIn • Portfolio • +234 816 910 3517

Integrating creativity, mindfulness & aesthetics in crafting accessible experiences & interactions.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A product designer with over 4 years of UX and UI design experience across web and mobile devices. I am enthusiastic, creative and adept at translating the product's goal into a useful user experience. Experienced program manager with a strong aptitude for problem-solving, communication, and the ability to make decisions in the client's best interests.

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

DESIGN TOOLS: Figma, Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe After Effects. **HARD SKILLS:** UI Design, UX Design, UX Research, Usability Testing, Heuristic Evaluation, Information Architecture, Design Software Proficiency, Wireframing, Prototyping, Interaction Design.

SOFT SKILLS: Communication, Creativity, Critical Thinking, Teamwork/Collaboration, Ownership, Problem Solving, Receptiveness to Feedback, Empathy, Flexibility.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

GRAFECT - Product Designer (May 2021 – Present)

- Worked in tandem with engineers, product managers and the overall UX team to design creative and intuitive design solutions for clients.
- Contributed to the creation, organization, and distribution or project style guides, pattern libraries, and asset repositories.
- Designed two proprietary onboarding features to help new users learn vital information about an event management application.
- Developed cost effective prototypes for initial testing and simulation.
- Launched a beta for an Online Store. Designed the onboarding, custom site editor, page templates, and order management flows. Provided design support for the Retail POS experience (alpha and beta). Built prototypes to test workflow optimizations for search and scan interaction patterns.

TRAVCUT EDUCATIONAL CONSULT - Product Designer (Sep 2020 - May 2021)

Spearheaded the design of a mobile application; its primary function is to help students
explore various scholarship opportunities abroad and also provide guidelines to help
interested students secure admission.

- Worked very closely with the development team to ensure for a seamless handoff process.
- Designed high-fidelity prototypes for a mobile application and carried out user testing to get feedback before making a handoff to the development team. This process helped eradicate costly and unnecessary changes during development.

WEBCOUPERS - Product Designer (Apr 2018 - Aug 2020)

- Conducted intensive research which included drafting user personas, competitive analysis, qualitative surveys and much more, to better define various problems. This made finding solutions much easier and refined.
- Designed a functional and visually appealing website interface for a multinational fintech company, to better orient users across pages.
- Re-designed the mobile application for a communications network company to improve the user experience, which led to the increase of customer retention by 18%
- Worked in tandem with the development team in order to ensure smooth and seamless handoff of product designs. This increased efficiency by 35%
- Designed high fidelity mock-ups for various brand websites, which was a very vital
 process needed to get refined customer feedback before the final interface designs were
 sent to the development team.
- Troubleshooting to find creative and functional solutions to various design problems was an indispensable measure in my process.

FREELANCER - Product Designer (Nov 2017 - Present)

o RAD

- Designed a modern shopping web interface and its interaction including a live chatting system and functionality that provided for an improved experience.
- Designed the information architecture to help organize information within the product to help ease user navigation.
- Responsible for maintaining design across web and mobile.

o GLC

- Designed the mobile application for GLC in collaboration with cross functional teams of engineers, product managers, marketers etc.
- Designed an in-app payment feature that allowed members make donations, pay
 offerings and other forms of transactions.

DEZIGN DECK

- Designed a responsive portfolio website for Dezign Deck, an interior design company in Lagos, Nigeria.
- Utilized figma's prototyping tool to design fully responsive prototypes to make user testing and handoff process easier.

· Designed interactions and micro animations.

VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

- o **Red Cross:** Volunteered as a red cross member in the NYSC program. During this period, I helped care for ailing members and administered first aid to them.
- o **AIESEC:** Came up with multiple visual designs that helped bring awareness to communities, development outreach, social activities and awareness to health-related issues like; cancer, STDs etc.

EDUCATION

BSc. Computer Science.